So, basically we have public leaders,
إذاً، في الأساس لدينا قادة في القطاع العام،
public officials who are out of control;
مسئولون خارج نطاق السيطرة.
they are writing bills that are unintelligible,
إنهم يكتبون قوانين غير واضحة.
and out of these bills are going to come
ونتائج هذه التشريعات ستصل ل
maybe 40,000 pages of regulations, total complexity,
ربما 40 ألف صحفة من القوانين، تعقيد كامل،
which has a dramatically negative impact on our life.
التي لديها تأثير سلبي كبير على حياتنا.
If you're a veteran coming back from Iraq or Vietnam
إذا كنت أحد قدامى المحاربين عائداً من العراق أو فيتنام
you face a blizzard of paperwork to get your benefits;
فأنك ستواجة عاصفة من الأعمال الورقية للحصول على معاملاتك.
if you're trying to get a small business loan,
إن كنت تحاول الحصول على قرض لعمل صغير،
you face a blizzard of paperwork.
فأنك ستواجه عاصفة من العمل الورقي.
What are we going to do about it? I define simplicity
ما الذي سنفعله تجاه ذلك؟ أنا أعرّف البساطة
as a means to achieving clarity,
بالوسيلة لتحقيق الوضوح،
transparency and empathy,
الشفافية والتعاطف،
building humanity into communications.
ببناء إنسانية داخل التواصل.
I've been simplifying things for 30 years.
لقد كنت أبسط الأشياء طوال 30 عاماً.
I come out of the advertising and design business.
لقد خرجت من قطاع أعمال الترويج والتصميم.
My focus is understanding you people,
وتخصصي هو فهمكم أنت أيها الناس،
and how you interact with the government
وكيف تتفاعلون مع الحكومة
to get your benefits,
للحصول على منافعكم،
how you interact with corporations to decide whom you're going to do business with,
كيف يمكن أن تتفاعل مع مؤسسات لتتخذ قرار حول من تعمل معه،
and how you view brands.
وكيف ترى العلامات التجارية.
So, very quickly, when President Obama said,
لذا، فبسرعة شديدة، عندما قال الرئيس أوباما،
"I don't see why we can't
" لا أعرف لماذا لا نستطيع
have a one-page, plain English consumer credit agreement."
الحصول على إتفاق إئتمان للمستهلك من صفحة واحدة."
So, I locked myself in a room,
لذا، أغلقت نفسي في غرفة،
figured out the content,
وتعرفت على المحتويات،
organized the document, and wrote it in plain English.
ونظمت الوثائق، وكتبتها بإنجليزية سهلة.
I've had this checked by the two top
وقمت بتدقيقها بواسطة أكبر
consumer credit lawyers in the country.
محاميين للإئتمان في هذا البلد.
This is a real thing.
هذا شئ حقيقي.
Now, I went one step further and said,
الآن، لقد ذهبت لخطوة أبعد وقلت،
"Why do we have to stick with the stodgy lawyers
" لماذا ينبغي علينا ملازمة محاميين متخمين
and just have a paper document? Let's go online."
ونعمل على مستندات ورقية فقط؟ لنذهب إلى الإنترنت."
And many people
إذاً، فالعديد من الناس
might need help in computation.
ربما يحتاجون مساعدة في الحسابات.
Working with the Harvard Business School,
بالعمل مع مدرسة هارفارد للأعمال،
you'll see this example when you talk about minimum payment:
سترى هذا المثال عندما تتحدث عن الدفع الأدنى.
If you spent 62 dollars for a meal,
إذا صرفت 62 دولارً لوجبة،
the longer you take to pay out that loan,
كلما طال زمان دفعك لذلك القرض،
you see, over a period of time using the minimum payment
كما ترون، بعد فترة من الزمن بإستخدام الدفع الأدنى
it's 99 dollars and 17 cents.
ستصل إلى 99 دولاراً و 17 سنتاً.
How about that? Do you think your bank is going to show that to people?
ماذا عن ذلك؟ هل تعتقد أن مصرفك سيقوم بعرض ذلك إلى الناس؟
But it's going to work. It's more effective
لكنها ستنجح. إنها أكثر فعاليةً
than just computational aids.
عوضاً عن العصر الحسابي فقط.
And what about terms like
وماذا عن مصطلحات مثل
"over the limit"?
فوق الحد؟
Perhaps a stealth thing.
ربما هو شئ غامض.
Define it in context. Tell people what it means.
قم بتعريفه في السياق. أخبر الناس ماذا يعني.
When you put it in plain English,
عندما تضعه بلغة إنجليزية سهلة
you almost force the institution
فأنك تقريباً ترغم المؤسسة
to give the people a way, a default out of that,
لتعطي الناس خياراً، تلقائياً من ذلك،
and not put themselves at risk.
وليس تعريض أنفسهم للمخاطر.
Plain English is about
لغة إنجليزية سهلة حول
changing the content.
تغيير المحتويات.
And one of the things I'm most proud of
وأحد الأشياء التي أنا فخور بها للغاية
is this agreement for IBM.
هي إتفاقية لشركة IBM.
It's a grid, it's a calendar.
إنها شبكة، إنها تقويم.
At such and such a date, IBM has responsibilities,
في تاريخ كذا وكذا، لشركة IBM مسئوليات،
you have responsibilities.
وعليك أنت مسئوليات.
Received very favorably by business.
تم الترحيب بها من قبل الأعمال.
And there is some good news to report today.
وهناك بعض الأخبار السارة لأطلعكم بها اليوم.
Each year, one in 10 taxpayers
كل عام واحد من كل 10 دافعي ضرائب
receives a notice from the IRS.
يتلقى إخطاراً من مصحلة الضرائب.
There are 200 million letters that go out.
هناك 200 مليون خطاب يتم إرسالهم.
Running through this typical letter that they had,
بالعمل بالوثيقة النموذجية التي لديهم،
I ran it through my simplicity lab,
التي قمت بتشخيصها في مختبر البساطة خاصتي،
it's pretty unintelligible.
إنها غير واضحة بتاتاً.
All the parts of the document in red are not intelligible.
كل أجزاء المستند باللون الأحمر ليست واضحة.
We looked at doing over 1,000 letters that cover
لقد نظرنا بتجربة أكثر من 1000 خطاب تغطي
70 percent of their transactions in plain English.
70% من المعاملات باللغة الإنجليزية السهلة.
They have been tested in the laboratory.
لقد تم إختبارها في المختبر.
When I run it through my lab,
عندما أختبرتها عبر مختبري
this heat-mapping shows everything
هذه المخطط يوضح كل شئ
is intelligible.
إنه واضح.
And the IRS has introduced the program.
وقد قامت مصلحة الضرائب بتقديم البرنامج.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
There are a couple of things going on right now
وهناك عدة أشياء جارية الآن
that I want to bring to your attention.
التي أريد لفت إنتباهكم إليها.
There is a lot of discussion now
هناك الكثير من النقاش الآن
about a consumer financial protection agency,
حول وكالة حماية المستهلك،
how to mandate simplicity.
كيف توصي بالبساطة.
We see all this complexity.
نحن نشهد كل هذا التعقيد.
It's incumbent upon us,
يتوجب علينا ..
and this organization, I believe,
وعلى هذه المؤسسة، كما أعتقد،
to make clarity, transparency
لجعل الوضوح، الشفافية،
and empathy a national priority.
والتعاطف كأولوية وطنية.
There is no way that we should allow government
لا يوجد مجال لكي نسمح للحكومة
to communicate the way they communicate.
بمخاطبتنا بنفس الطريقة التي يخاطبونا بها.
There is no way we should do business
لا يوجد مجال يلزمنا لممارسة العمل
with companies that have agreements
مع شركات لديها إتفاقات
with stealth provisions and that are unintelligible.
مع فقرات غامضة وليست واضحة.
So, how are we going to change the world?
لذا، كيف سنقوم بتغيير العالم؟
Make clarity, transparency and simplicity a national priority.
لنحقق الوضوح، الشفافية والبساطة كأولوية وطنية.
I thank you.
شكراً لكم
(Applause)
(تصفيق)